MATEUS M. FURQUIM MENDONÇA

Machine Learning and Software Engineer

@mfurquimdev@gmail.com

git mfurquimdev

in/mfurquimdev

@mfurquim.dev

Brazil

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly skilled software engineer with over 9 years of experience and a diverse background. Committed to team growth and innovation through effective mentoring and collaboration. Strong problem-solving skills with a passion for delivering high-quality software solutions.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Back-end Developer

📋 Jan 2021 - Present

DevGrid

United Kingdom (Remote)

Managed several microservices that employ machine learning algorithms to estimate house appliances' energy consumption.

- > Achieved up to 59% improvement in **Python** write operations on **Cassandra** through the safe utilization of unlogged batches.
- > Iteratively improved domain models following **Domain Driven Design** approach, increasing efficiency in delivering new features.

Embedded Software Developer

Autotrac

Nov 2019 - Aug 2020

Prasília, DF - Brazil

Maintained security and logistic features of an embedded system for a customized hardware and Linux kernel.

- > Employed dependency injection and other SOLID principles to enhance C++ code quality and maintainability.
- > Implemented monitoring solutions to gather real-time performance data, ensuring optimal system efficiency and responsiveness.

DevOps Consultant

IBM

🗂 Jan 2019 - Nov 2019

Prasília, DF - Brazil

Collaborated with multiple teams to improve observability of the back-end services of a prominent banking institution.

- > Contributed to self-discovering services feature using etcd key-value store, consistent hashing and a federation of Prometheus.
- > Employed **PromQL** to develop alerts that detected low performance of new deployments and potential DDoS attacks.

INTERN EXPERIENCE

EDUCATION

Online

LANGUAGES

Ligature A merged glyph.

Kerning A spacing adjustment between two adjacent letters.

In this report, we will explore the various factors that influence fluid dynamics in glaciers and how they contribute to the formation and behaviour of these natural structures.

Sub Heading

- 1. The climate
 - Temperature
 - Precipitation
- 2. The topography
- 3. The geology

The equation $Q = \rho Av + C$ defines the glacial flow rate.

The flow rate of a glacier is defined by the following equation:

$$Q = \rho A v + C$$

The flow rate of a glacier is given by the following equation:

 $Q = \rho A v + \text{time offset}$

Total displaced soil by glacial flow:

$$7.32\beta + \sum_{i=0}^{\nabla} \frac{Q_i}{2}$$

Total displaced soil by glacial flow:

MATEUS M. FURQUIM MENDONÇA

$$7.32\beta + \sum_{i=0}^{\nabla} \frac{Q_i(a_i - \varepsilon)}{2}$$

$$v \coloneqq \begin{pmatrix} x_1 \\ x_2 \\ x_3 \end{pmatrix}$$

Number: 3

-x is the opposite of x

let name = [Typst!]

parbreak()

strong emphasis print(1) https://typst.app/

HEADING

- item
- 1. item

Term description

 x^2

'single' or "double" , -



Tweet at us #ad,

 x^2

$$\begin{array}{c} x \\ x_1 \ x^2 \ 1 + \frac{a+b}{5} \ y \end{array}$$